-==www.RagBear.com==-
福尔摩斯探案集  第3季第2集
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业用途
-=Keepfrds MNHD Team=-
校对: ptrpan
格兰其庄园
巴纳
Barna.
起来 华生
Come, Watson,
快起来
come.
事情十分急迫
The game is afoot.
穿好衣服赶快走
Get your clothes and come.
我想我们俩
Well I think we have
已经很默契了 福尔摩斯
thawed sufficiently Holmes.
没错
Splendid.
肯特 玛尔舍姆 格兰其庄园 下午3:30
Abbey Grange, Marsham, Kent, 3:30 a.m.
亲爱的福尔摩斯先生
My Dear Mr. Holmes
我希望你能够立刻协助我
I should be very glad of your immediate assistance
解决这桩极特殊的案件
in what promises to be a most remarkable case.
处理这一类案件正是你的特长
There's something quite in your line.
除去已把那位女士放开之外
Except for releasing the lady
现场一切东西
I will see that everything is kept
都未移动
exactly as I have found it,
我请求你火速赶来
but I beg you not to lose an instant,
因为单独留下优斯塔斯爵士是不妥当的
as it is difficult to leave Sir Eustace there.
您的忠实朋友
Yours faithfully.
斯坦莱・霍普金
Stanley Hopkins.
霍普金巡关
Inspector Hopkins.
他找我到现场
He's called you in seven times,
曾有七次 每次
on each occasion his summons
确实都急需我的帮助
has been entirely justified.
我想你一定已经把他的案子
I fancy that every one of his cases
全收到你的文集里去了
has found its way into your collection,
我承认
and I must admit, Watson,
你很会选材
you do have some power of selection.
谢谢
Thank you.
这弥补了你
Which atones for much of which I deplore
叙述上的缺陷
about your narratives.
你看待一切问题总是
Your fatal habit of looking at everything
从写故事的角度出发
from the point of view of a story
而不是从科学破案的角度
instead of as a scientific exercise
这样就毁坏了
has ruined what might have been
这些典型案例的
an instructive and even classical
示范性和教益性
series of demonstrations.
你为什么不自己写呢?
Why did you not write them yourself?
我会写的 华生
I will, my dear Watson, I will,
我会在我晚年的时候写的
in my declining years.
我们现在要侦查的
So our present research
像是一件谋杀案
appears to be one of murder.
是吗?
Does it?
信上有E B两个字母
'E. B.' monogram,
组成的图案做为家徽
coat-of-arms,
这个地址曾经
with an address which harks back
是修道院
to the dissolution of the monasteries.
他们生活在上流社会
They're moving in high-life.
布莱肯斯特尔
Brackenstall.
优斯塔斯・布莱肯斯特尔爵士
Sir Eustace Brackenstall.
你听说过他?
You've heard of him?
他是有史以来
He was quoted in The Chronicle the other day
肯特郡最大的富翁
as being one of the richest men in Kent.
华生 你真是知识渊博
Watson, you are a treasury of knowledge.
这么说你认为他已经死了?
And you think him dead?
我认为他被谋杀了 华生
I think him murdered, Watson.
霍普金并不是易动感情的人
Hopkins is not an emotional man.
他的信说明他心情相当激动
The writing shows a certain agitation.
事情一定很紧急
It is surely urgent.
你认为尸体是否还留在那
You think the body left there
等着我们去验尸?
for our own inspection?
我想我们会发现
I think that we shall find
布莱肯斯特尔家的人已经所剩无几了
the Brackenstall line is now extinct.
你们能来我真高兴 福尔摩斯先生
Very good of you to come, Mr. Holmes.
你也是 医生
And you, Doctor.
巡官
Inspector.
希望你能原谅我 福尔摩斯先生
I hope you forgive me, Mr. Holmes.
原谅你什么 霍普金?
Forgive what, Hopkins?
要不是事情紧急 也不会来麻烦你
I should not have troubled you sir.
现在那位女士已经苏醒过来
But since the lady has come to herself,
她把事情讲得很清楚
she has given me so clear an account of the affair
所以我们要做的事不多了
that well there's not much left for us to do.
你还记得路易珊姆那伙强盗吗?
You remember the Lewisham gang?
就是那三个姓阮达尔的吗?
The ring of three Randalls?
正是
Exactly sir
父亲和两个儿子
the father and two sons.
是他们干的
It's their work.
这毫无疑问
Not a doubt.
两周前他们在西顿汉姆做了案
But they did a job at Sydenham a fortnight ago
有人看到了他们并报了案
They did, they were seen and described.
他们真是残忍
Well it's cool and I agree
这么快就又害人了
to do another so soon and so near,
一定是他们干的
but it is they,
应该把他们绞死
and a hanging matter this time.
那么优斯塔斯爵士死了?
Brackenstall is dead, then?
是的 医生
Awe yes, Doctor.
就在餐厅里
In the dining room,
他的头部
his head was knocked in
被通条打破了
with his own poker.
那女士呢?
And the lady?
他们去过餐厅了吗?
Have they been in the dining room yet?
还没 夫人
Not yet, my lady.
你的周到安排让我感到欣慰
I shall be glad when you can arrange matters.
那是什么?
What is that?
您的伤不止一处 夫人!
You have other injuries, madam!
这没什么
It's nothing.
这和夜里的惨案没有关系
It has no connection with this hideous business.
请坐吧
Please sit down.
我把一切关于
I think it would be best
优斯塔斯爵士的事
to inform you of something gentlemen
都告诉你们
regarding Sir Eustace.
你们无疑会听到
You'll no doubt hear a rumor of it otherwise
他人歪曲事实的
from idol tongues
闲言碎语
who'll distort the truth of it.
以这种方式玷污他的人格
It would pain me to think
让我备受痛苦
of his memory tarnished in that way.
但我还是得说
Sir Eustace drank
优斯塔斯爵士嗜酒成癖
I'm afraid.
没有规律 反复无常
Not regularly, inconsistently.
但并不会影响我们的婚姻
Not in a way to hurt our marriage.
也没有妨碍
Nor did it interfere
他执行公务的能力
with the exercise of his public duties.
尽管如此
Nevertheless,
这一恶习仍是家族丑闻
the vice was a private shame to him.
我不喜欢他的恶习 对此他十分在意
He was very sensible of my dislike of it.
当他酒瘾发作时
When he felt the obsession to keenly
他就会完全放纵自己
he took himself off
喝得烂醉
until the poison had exhausted him.
他的做法自然
It distressed me of course
让我悲痛万分
that it should happen
但他仍保持着自尊
but he was proud and sensitive enough
从不让我看见他烂醉的模样
never to allow me to witness it.
对此 我很感激
I felt deep gratitude for that
而且深表同情
and not a little pity.
你能明白吗 先生?
Can you understand that gentlemen?
我从未听过有人在谈起这类事情时
I have never heard a like case talked of
还怀着深切的同情 夫人
with such illuminating compassion madam.
我想还有件事
I must, however, ask you
会让你更惊奇的
to believe something further.
对于拥有如此恶习的丈夫
I was in some measure grateful
我仍是很感激的
for this vice of my husband's.
怎么会?
How could that be?
我是在澳大利亚南部
I spent most of my life in South Australia,
一个靠近阿得雷德的
in the wine growing country
酿酒村庄长大的
near Adelaide.
在我很小时
As a very young woman
我就和我父亲生活在一起
I lived alone with my father.
我妈妈已经去世
My mother was dead.
真要说谁给了我母爱
If I had a mother
那就是我忠诚的梯芮萨
it was my loyal Theresa.
那是一段非常自由的生活
It was a very free life.
我发现我很难
I found it extremely difficult
在英国适应
to adapt to the proprieties of England
庄园夫人这样的身份
being mistress of such a place as this.
所以我想 如果
So I felt if I would
对于我丈夫的恶习
just show a decent understanding
表达出更大的宽容
of my husband's weakness
相反 他也会
he would, in turn,
原谅我一些失礼的举动
forgive me for my unsuitable behavior.
而事实也正是如此
And so it proved.
我明白了
I see.
现在我来告诉你昨晚的事
I'll tell you about last night.
优斯塔斯爵士大约10点半休息
Eustace retired about half-past ten.
仆人们都已经回到自己的屋子
The servants had already gone to their quarters.
他们的屋子在哪?
Which are where?
在东翼
In the East Wing.
只有我的丈夫 梯芮萨和我
Only my husband, Theresa and myself
住在正中部分
sleep in the central block.
其他仆人听不到这的响声
The servants would have heard nothing.
你那时休息了吗?
Had you retired by then?
我在自己的房间
I was in my room.
在夫人未上床休息前我是不会休息的
I never retire until I've seen madam to bed.
谢谢
Thank you.
我还未睡下
I sat up,
就坐在这屋子里
this room in fact.
我有个习惯就是
It is my custom to walk around
睡前总要检查下房屋是否安全
to see that the house is secure
因为显而易见
because for obvious reasons,
优斯塔斯爵士
Sir Eustace
在这方面
is not always to be relied upon
是靠不住的
in that respect.
我先去猎枪室
I went into the gun-room,
厨房
the kitchen,
食起室
the butler's pantry,
弹子房
the billiard-room,
客厅
the drawing-room,
最后是餐厅
and finally the dining-room
看到窗帘没拉上
where the curtains were drawn.
很难告诉你
It's difficult to tell you
之后发生了什么
much of what happened next.
我走到窗前
I took a step towards the curtain
迎面站着
and I found myself
一个闯入者
face-to-face with an intruder.
体型庞大
A big man,
年过半百
quite elderly.
我们对视了一会
For a moment we just stared at each other.
然后有两个男人出现在他背后
Then two other men came in behind him
这个人立即向我扑来
and he came for me.
我一定是昏过去了
I must have been unconscious
好几分钟
for some minutes.
正在这时我倒霉的丈夫
It was then that my unfortunate husband
来到餐厅
entered the room.
正如你们看到的 他们杀了他
They dealt with him as you shall see.
我又一次昏过去 我也不确定
I believe I fainted again, I'm not sure.
具体的事很难...
The exact events are difficult...
我时而清醒 时而昏迷
I drifted in and out of consciousness,
你能理解吗?
you understand?
我知道他们
I do know that they
拿走了屋子里的银器
cleared the room of its silver
他们给自己开了瓶
and they must have drawn themselves
波特酒
a bottle of port,
我看到他们喝酒了
some of which I saw them drink.
袭击我的人
The man who struck me
是个留有胡须的中年人
was elderly with a beard.
另外两个年轻人
The others younger,
面部很干净
smooth faced.
是的
Yes.
他们走过来看看是否已把我缚紧
Finally they checked that I was securely bound
然后带着银器离开了
and left taking the silver with them.
你是何时发觉情况不对的?
How was the alarm raised?
夫人一直没有上楼
Madam had not come upstairs.
早前她说过在我之后就会上楼
Early she said she would follow me shortly
所以到了午夜 我就下楼看看
so at midnight I went down
以防她又抱着书睡着了
in case she had fallen asleep over her book.
我讨厌抱着书睡着
A thing I hate to do.
于是我就发现了夫人 可怜的人儿
And there I found her, poor lamb,
正如她说的
just as she says
爵士倒在地板上
and him on the floor,
他的血和脑浆溅了一屋子
his blood and brains all over the room.
这些事足以使她吓昏过去
Enough to drive a woman out of her wits.
她被绑在那儿 还被塞住了嘴
And her gagged and bound
衣服上还溅上了许多血点
and her very dress spotted with him.
要不是这位澳大利亚阿得雷德港的
She never wanted courage,
玛丽・弗莱泽夫人 也就是格兰其庄园的
did Miss Mary Fraser of Adelaide,
布莱肯斯特尔夫人变得性格坚强
and Lady Brackenstall of Abbey Grange
那她早就失去生活的勇气了
has learned new ways.
你们询问她的时间已经够长了
You've questioned her long enough, gentlemen.
这位夫人和她的女仆
When did the lady and the maid
是何时离开澳大利亚的?
come from Australia?
大约十八个月前
About eighteen months ago, sir.
她爸爸送她
Her father sent her
来欧洲体验生活
to get her experience of Europe.
实际是为了找个丈夫吧?
That is to a find a husband?
可怜的女人那时一定以为嫁了个好夫君
Poor woman must have seen the bruited match.
现场一片狼藉 先生
It's a mess sir.
警官
Constable.
的确是一片狼藉
A mess indeed.
他们没有碰过任何东西
They've touched nothing sir.
你有何看法 医生?
What do you make of it, Doctor?
我可以验下尸吗?
Should I?
可以 我亲爱的朋友
Please proceed my dear fellow.
一击毙命
Why it's a blow.
狠狠地一击
Of savage velocity.
只有一击吗?
A single blow?
我想是的
I believe so.
你看 伤口很明显
It is a straightforward enough wound, you see
从耳部开始
it begins thus below the ear
以这个角度
and then crosses both spheres
伤至顶骨
of the parietal bone at such an angle.
而这一边则被
That this side is smashed
击致颅缝
as far as the cranial suture.
我从未见过这样的伤口
I've never seen anything like it.
这个上了年纪的阮达尔 力气一定很大
A powerful man, this elder Randall.
他干的一半勾当都和暴力有关
Half his trade is violence sir.
显然这次他也运用了自己的优势
He certainly left his trademark.
让我想不通的是
What beats me
既然他们知道
is how Randall could do so mad a thing,
夫人能说出他们的外貌
knowing that the lady could describe them,
并且我们也能认出他们
and that we could not fail
为什么他们还会做出这种蠢事
to recognize the description.
犯罪心理是难以捉摸的
The criminal mind has its quirks
也许有时会带有良知的顾虑
of consciousness scruples.
从这个角度考虑
In that respect,
此案与其他案件一样拥有独特奇怪之处
it is as individual and curious as any other.
这位夫人也许看似吝啬 实则十分慷慨
A noted miser, Lady, secretly charitable
所以残暴的阮达尔打消了
so this violent Randall may draw the line
杀死这位昏迷的夫人的念头
at the murder of an unconscious woman.
要不就是他确信
Or he may well believe
这位夫人没有看到他
that she did not see him.
这怎么可能呢 先生?
Well how is that sir?
她说他们俩对视了一会儿
She testifies that they stared at each other.
没错 但拿着蜡烛的是她
Yes but it was she who held the light.
而阮达尔看到的
What Randall may have seen
极有可能只是闪烁的烛光
was mostly flickering candle flame.
烛光后的相貌
The face behind it,
只是模糊的影子罢了
a distorted mask.
他也许没想到
He may be not imaginative enough
她看到的
to have thought that she saw
并不比他清楚
anymore than he did.
所以他立马打昏了她
He knocked her unconscious at the next instance,
这样就可以达到他的目的
thus for his purposes
彻底解决问题...华生?
solving his problem... Watson?
你能检查下土耳其地毯吗?
May I impose upon you to search the Turkey rug?
检查地毯干吗 福尔摩斯?
What for Holmes?
看看是否有蜡滴 华生
Candle wax, Watson, candle wax.
这条铃绳很有问题
Now this bell presents a mystery,
不是吗 巡官?
does it not Inspector?
先生
Sir.
绳子往下一拉
When this was pulled down
厨房的铃声应该是很响的
the bell in the kitchen must have rung loudly.
由于厨房的位置
No one would hear it
没人能听得到
the way the kitchen is placed.
这个情况强盗怎么会知道的呢?
How did the burglar know that?
确实 福尔摩斯先生
Exactly, Mr. Holmes, exactly.
这个问题 我也反复考虑过
For the very question I've put myself.
强盗一定很熟悉这栋房子
Now either he has known the house
要不他准和
or he may have dealings
某个仆人有勾结
with one of the servants.
我的手下正在
One of my men is going over the record of service
警局给仆役长
at the station with the butler,
录笔录
at this very moment sir.
巡官 你考虑得很周到
Inspector, you seem to have thought of everything.
谢谢你 福尔摩斯先生
Thank you, Mr. Holmes.
福尔摩斯?
Holmes?
怎么了 华生?
What is it Watson?
看
There.
一小滴蜡
A scattering of wax
而且有轻微地硫化
and a very light scorching.
已经清理掉了
Invisible,
但仍留有其独特的味道
but leaving it's characteristic scent.
夫人一定是在这昏倒的
The lady would have fallen here.
而阮达尔迅速
Randall would have snatched up
接住了烛台
the candelabra immediately.
我想他们在那
I suppose that is
吃了些小点心
where they took their refreshment.
是的 以此缓解紧张的心情
To steady their nerves, yes.
是波特酒 先生
Port wine, sir.
布莱肯斯特尔夫人有说
Did Lady Brackenstall say
他们用拔塞钻了吗?
that the butler's corkscrew was used?
没有 先生
No sir.
这伙强盗开酒瓶的时候
She was senseless at the moment
她已经失去了知觉
the bottle was opened.
的确是这样
Quite so.
他们是用螺旋器开瓶的
It was opened with a pocket screw,
很有可能是小刀上带的螺旋
probably contained in a knife.
仔细观察软木塞的上部可以看出
If you examine the top of the cork you will observe
螺旋插了三次
that the screw was driven in three times
才拔出软木塞
before the cork was extracted.
其实用拔塞钻卡住瓶塞
This long screw would have transfixed it
一下便能拔出来
and drawn it with a single pull.
你抓到这个人的时候
When you catch this fellow,
你会发现
it is likely that you will find
他身上有把多用小刀
that he has a multiplex knife in his possession.
分析得妙极了 福尔摩斯先生
Excellent, Mr. Holmes.
这三个玻璃杯
These three glasses
确实困扰着我
do puzzle me,
这我必须承认
I must confess.
布莱肯斯特尔夫人确实
Did Lady Brackenstall say
看见这三个人喝酒了?
that she actually saw the three men drinking?
是的 这一点她记得很清楚
Awe yes, she was clear about that, sir.
那么 这个情况就说到这儿
Well then there is an end of it.
还有什么可说的吗?
What more is to be said?
巡官 也许像夏洛克・福尔摩斯
Perhaps, Inspector, when a man has special powers
这样拥有非凡能力的人
and special knowledge, like Sherlock Holmes,
当遇到一个极其简单的问题时
it rather encourages him
追求复杂的答案
to seek a complex explanation
才能让他欢欣鼓舞
when a simpler one is at hand.
一抓到阮达尔就通知我们
You let us know when Randall is arrested.
可怜的福尔摩斯 你现在一定很郁闷
Poor Holmes, you must feel like an abstruse.
一个有学识的专家
A learned specialist
却被邀请去解决一个豆大点的事
calling for a case of measles
很烦人吧
Annoying.
我们必须得回去
We must return.
那三个玻璃杯
Three glasses.
华生
Watson,
夫人的美貌
We have been dazzled out of observation
影响了我们的判断力
by that lady's beauty,
她美是事实
beauty may be truth
但她没有必要说那件事啊
but she does not necessarily speak it.
三个杯子全沾了酒
There was port in each glass
可是只有一个杯子里有渣滓
but there was only crusting in one glass.
倒酒时最后一杯
Last glass filled
很可能是有渣滓的
is the one most likely to contain the crusting.
没错
I agree.
但前提是倒最后一杯酒时
If the last pouring it
瓶中已所剩无几
had approached the bottom of the bottle
但瓶子中仍还有半瓶
but the bottle was half full
而如果倒之前摇晃过的话
and it had been agitated.
那三杯中都应有渣滓
The crusting was present throughout the port.
那你是怎么想的?
Well what then do you suppose?
其实只用了两个杯子
That only two glasses were used
两个杯子的渣滓
and the drinks of both
都倒在第三个杯子里
were poured into a third
所以产生了假象
to give us the false impression
好像有三个人在那儿喝酒
that three people were there.
我明白了
I understand.
如果我的推测没错 华生
If I'm right Watson then in an instant
这个案件立刻变成
this case rises from the common place
一件很不寻常的案子
to the exceeding and remarkable.
那应该就是去肯特郡的火车了
That would be the Kent train.
哪里?      那里
What way?        That way.
你听到火车声了?
How on earth did you hear it?
我什么也没听到 华生
I heard nothing Watson,
我观察得来的
I observed.
荒废了一个早晨后
Salutary thought
该好好思考了
after such a misspent morning.
布莱肯斯特尔夫人和她的女仆
Lady Brackenstall and her maid
掩护罪犯
must have some very good reason
一定有重大的理由
for shielding the real criminal.
好了 华生
Well Watson,
我们得靠自己
we shall just have to construct our case
设法弄清当时的情况
for ourselves without depth.
快去格兰其庄园
The Abbey Grange as fast as you can.
华生
Watson.
看来斯坦莱・霍普金
Well it appears that Inspector Hopkins
已经去总部汇报
has gone to report to headquarters.
太好了 我们可以采取主动了
Splendid, then we can take possession.
对于辛苦劳作的人
How many frustrated episodes
在这块布满废铁的坟地上
for the laboring men here
重建家园
could one reconstruct
要经历多少苦难啊?
from this mechanical cemetery?
那是什么
What's this?
华生?
Watson?
看起来似乎不完整
Not entirely mechanical it seems.
法吉
Fudge.
愿灵魂安息
Requiescat in pace.
我认为这应该是宠物的墓碑
I imagine it's a pet's gravestone.
它已经被打碎过了
It has been smashed.
然后被修补 接着再被打碎
Mended and smashed again
这是有意为之
with deliberate force.
它告诉了我们发生在不久之前的事件
The story it tells is of the immediate past.
华生?
Watson?
一块残缺的狗项圈
The remnants of a dog's collar.
法吉
Fudge.
嗨 你
Hey you!
在上个月里 这个庄园有没有
Has any servant been dismissed from the house
一位仆人被辞退?
in the last month?
没有 先生
No sir.
那么就和我想象的一样
Then it's as I thought.
法吉
Fudge.
布莱肯斯特尔夫人的宠物狗
Lady Brackenstall's pet dog,
让我们猜想一下 死亡
let us imagine, dies.
一定不难想象
It may not be too fanciful to suggest
这个可怜的不幸的动物
that the poor unfortunate creature
是被谋杀的
was literally killed.
被谋杀?
Killed?
因为什么
For what reason?
我认为原因是很难猜到的
Reason I suggest hardly entered into it.
应该源于一场能够称为疯狂虐杀的事件
It was done in a fit of insane rage.
被谁?
By whom?
一个酒鬼 一个残酷成性的恶棍
By a drunkard, sadistic ruffian.
其中一个凶手?
One of the murderers?
不 华生
No Watson.
那位夫人的丈夫
The lady's husband.
布莱肯斯特尔的最后一代
The last of the Brackenstall's.
布莱肯斯特尔
Brackenstall.
你想想
Consider it.
除了这个家的主人 没有人
No one but a member of the household
可以破坏墓碑
could vandalize a gravestone
还把它留在原地
and it remain in place.
我有些困惑为什么
Why should Brackenstall
布莱肯斯特尔先生要这么对待
entertain such an obsession
一只宠物 似乎他再也
about a pet animal
不愿意留下任何关于它的回忆
that he would forbid any remembrance of it?
你也看到了那位夫人胳膊上的伤痕了
You saw the marks of course on the lady's arm.
是的 我很惊讶
Yes I was surprised
那没有引起你过多的兴趣
that it did not interest you more.
那些伤口应该是
They were stab wounds
长缝衣针或者帽针造成的
made by a long needle or a hatpin.
这位夫人已经生活在对自己
This lady has been living in fear
人身安全的恐惧中很长时间了 华生
of her physical safety Watson.
小心点 福尔摩斯
Take care Holmes.
华生
Watson?
我们的案子解决了
We have got our case.
我差点犯了个最严重的错误
Highly likely, the blunder of a lifetime.
但是现在整个谋杀过程就快完整了
But now the chain is almost complete.
你弄清哪些人是罪犯了?
You got your men?
是一个罪犯 华生
Man, Watson, man.
只有一个罪犯
Only one,
但是是个非常难对付的人
but a remarkable person.
他健壮得像头狮子 灵活得像只松鼠
Strong as a lion, active as a squirrel,
他的手很灵巧 而且
dexterous with his fingers and finally,
他的头脑也异常地聪明
remarkably quick-witted.
啊 布莱肯斯特尔夫人
Awe, Lady Brackenstall.
我不希望给您造成
I do not wish to cause you
不必要的苦恼
any unnecessary trouble,
我的愿望是让事情
my whole desire
更快解决让你摆脱痛苦
is to make things easier for you.
我知道您已经遭受了很多的磨难
I am convinced that you are a much-tried woman.
如果您愿意把我当做
If you will trust me
朋友一样地信任
and treat me as a friend,
您会发现我不会辜负您的诚意
you may find that I will justify that trust.
你要我做什么呢
What do you want me to do?
告诉我真实的情况
To tell me the truth.
福尔摩斯先生
Mr. Holmes!
不不不不 布莱肯斯特尔夫人
No, no, no, no please, Lady Brackenstall,
掩盖是没有用的
it is of no use.
你也许听过我
You may have heard of
所享有的小名声
a little reputation that I may possess,
我用我的名誉担保
I will stake it all on the fact
你所讲的完全是编造的
that your story is a complete fabrication.
你是个无耻的家伙
You're an impudent fellow.
你是不是说我的女主人撒谎了
You try to say that my mistress has told a lie?
你没有什么要和我说的了吗
Have you nothing to tell me?
我全说了
I have told you everything.
布莱肯斯特尔夫人 再想一想
Now think just once more, Lady Brackenstall.
坦率一些不是更好吗
Wouldn't it be better to be frank?
我知道的都说了
I have told you all I know.
对不起
I am sorry.
铃绳给了我们提示
The bell rope gave us the clue,
我的推论绝对没错
which should have left us in no doubt.
到底怎么一回事呢
How is that?
华生 如果你想把铃绳拉下来
If you were to pull down a bell rope, Watson,
你认为绳子应当从哪儿断呢
where would you expect it to break?
当然是在最上面
Surely at the top
与铁丝相接的地方
where it is attached to the wire.
而不是离铁丝三英寸的地方
Not three inches from the top.
但是绳子是磨损的
But the rope was frayed.
那个绑住夫人的绳子是被磨损的
The rope, which held Lady Brackenstall, was frayed.
这人很狡猾 用刀子故意磨损绳子的一头
He was cunning enough to do that with his knife.
可是另外一头没有磨损
But the other end was not.
如果你像我一样从壁炉架上看
If you would have stood on the mantelpiece as I did
你会看到另一头切得很平 没有磨损痕迹
you would have seen that it was cut through.
请停下
Stop.
马夫
Please driver.
华生
Watson?
这个圆木从今天早上就没有移动过
That log has not moved since early this morning.
有东西阻碍了它移动
Well perhaps it's snagged on something.
抑或是它被固定了
Or anchored.
保证霍普金会在他回来
See that Inspector Hopkins
的路上拿到这个 明白吗
gets this on his return, will you?
车站
Chilehurst station.
现在要去哪 福尔摩斯
Where to now Holmes?
跨南航线的海运公司的办公室
The shipping office of the Southern Cross Line.
对 当然了
Yes, yes of course.
跨南航线
The Southern Cross Line
主要承运从阿得雷德
is the principal passenger carrier
到伦敦的客人
between Adelaide and London.
哦 我懂了
Ah, I see.
那年五月
In May of that year,
只有一条航船到了英国港口
only one of ours reached the home port,
这条船叫"直布罗陀磐石"号
our flagship the Rock of Gibraltar.
我会把乘客名单给你的
I'll have the passenger list sent up.
福尔摩斯先生究竟是怎么知道的?
How on earth did Mr. Holmes know that?
哦  找到了
Awe, here we are.
阿得雷德的玛丽・弗莱泽夫人 头等舱
Miss Mary Fraser of Adelaide, first class,
她的女仆在旁陪同
accompanied by her maid.
直布罗陀磐石号现在在哪
Where is the Rock of Gibraltar now?
我去查查就知道了
I'll know today.
福尔摩斯先生 她现在
She was steaming west
正向西通过阿拉伯海湾
through the Arabian Gulf, Mr. Holmes,
前往苏伊士运河
heading for Suez, I hope.
你们的政策是
Is it your policy
经常调整船与船之间的人手的吗
to transfer officers much between ship and ship?
不是 恰恰相反
No not at all.
我们的政策是尽量不要这样
It is our policy not to.
哦 我明白你的意思了 先生
Awe, I have you, Mr. Holmes.
你想问我在这艘船上
You are asking the whereabouts
工作的某个船员
of a member of the crew of the Rock
常常在这艘船上工作
who has been seen very recently
但是此次却不在船上的船员
but not on the ship.
先生 你的理解能力真让我惊讶
Mr. Viviali, your precocity astonishes me.
我要告诉你 我是看了
I assure you it is only through study of
您这位好医生所描写您工作的精彩故事
the good doctor's masterly exposition of your work
才学会了您推理能力的一点皮毛
that I now have any small capacity to reason.
真的?
Really?
真让我惊奇
You amaze me.
华生 你不做笔记吗
Watson are you taking notes?
还有 您会非常高兴地听到
Also, you will be pleased to hear
我知道您要找的人是谁
that I know exactly who the officer is.
哦 太棒了
Awe, excellent,
布贝吉太太
Mrs. Burbage,
太棒了
excellent.
是的 各位先生
Yes gentlemen,
现在唯一是这艘船的船员
the only officer from that voyage of the Rock
却不在这艘船上的人
who is not aboard her now,
是杰克・克洛克
is Jack Croker,
一位出色的小伙子
a magnificent chap.
难道我说得不对吗 布贝吉太太
Am I not correct Mrs. Burbage?
克洛克有个缺点
Croker has a defect.
他是个讨人喜的同事
A delightful fellow.
帅气得就像一个王子
Handsome as a prince.
船员崇拜他
The crew worship him.
我们也将他提升为我们的
And we've promoted him to captain
新船"巴斯磐石"号的船长
of our new vessel the Bass Rock.
不用给我沏茶了
No tea for me please.
这是艘刚刚装修好的新船
Which is just fitting out.
他是我们最年轻的船长
He's the youngest captain we have
但是将会是最好的
but he'll be the best.
没有任何一个船长可以比得上他
Not an officer in the fleet to touch him.
他性情急噪
He is hot headed
容易激动
and excitable
但是忠诚
but loyal,
诚实
honest
而且是个热心肠
and kind-hearted.
有些时候在你的生命里
Sometimes in this life
你遇到了那种
you meet people who are,
你也许会叫做 拥有大智慧
what you might call, large-souled,
来自上天恩典的人
who are a privilege to know.
克洛克就是这样的人
Croker is one of those.
在我的工作中曾经有一两次
Once or twice in my career
由于我查出罪犯而造成的害处
I feel I've done more real harm
要比犯罪事件本身
about my discovery of the criminal
所造成的害处更大
than ever he had done by his crime.
我现在已经懂得需要谨慎
But I've learned caution now,
我最好是哄骗一下
and I'd rather play tricks
英国的法律
with the law of England
而不是我的良心
than with my own conscience.
船长克洛克
Captain Croker,
请坐
sit down.
我收到了你的电报
I've got your telegram,
并且按照你的要求准时来了
and I've come at the hour you said.
我听说你去过办公室
I heard you've been down to the office.
我是无法从你手里逃脱了?
There's no getting away from you is there?
大声说出来啊
Speak up, man.
你不能站在那里
You can't stand there
和我玩猫捉老鼠的把戏啊
and play cat and mouse with me!
你到底知道什么了
What do you know?
华生 能给他一支雪茄吗
Would you give him a cigar, Watson?
拜托
Please.
克洛克船长 抽抽烟
Bite on that,Captain Croker,
你要控制住自己的感情
and try not to let your nerves run away with you.
如果我把你当成罪犯 我就不会
I shall not sit here smoking with you
坐在这儿和你一起抽烟了
if I thought you were a common criminal.
告诉我
Tell me
你是用什么来
what did you use
让银器被固定在漂浮的圆木上的呢
to secure the silver to the floating log?
我猜想是用猎枪室的鱼线
My guess it's was fishing gut from the gun-room
但是银器被取出来时我不在现场
but I was not present at its recovery.
我说的对吗
Am I right?
你想要得到什么
What do you want?
正义
Justice.
为谁?
For whom?
这不重要
It doesn't matter.
我们只是想看到正义得以伸张
We just want to see justice done that is all.
很好
Very well.
是鱼线吗
Was it fishing gut?
不 是麻线
No, twine.
这是一个年轻水手
It was a throw back to the days
必须要掌握的东西
before the master as a youngster.
甚至现在我都会随身带着一枚银币
Even now I always carry a silver coin
和长麻线
and length twine...
还有一把多用小刀?
And a multiplex knife?
你到底是怎么知道的
How in the devil do you know that?
你到底是谁
Who are you?
现在
Now,
对我老老实实地讲讲
give me a true account of everything
昨晚在格兰其庄园发生的事
that happened at the Abbey Grange last night.
你对我坦白 我们还可以好好谈谈
Be frank with me and we may do some good.
对我耍花招的话
Play tricks with me
我就毁了你
and I'll crush you.
那我就豁出去了
I'll chance it.
但是有一点我要先说清楚
But one thing I'll say first,
我毫不后悔
I regret nothing,
也不害怕
I fear nothing
如果再遇到一次 我还会这样做
and I'd do it all again if I had to
并且以此自豪 那个该死的家伙
and be proud of the job, damn the man!
但只有我 是我一个人干的
Well that's my side of things, only my side.
当我想到玛丽
When I think of Mary,
亲爱的玛丽・弗莱泽
sweet Mary Fraser,
一想到我使她
I think of getting her
陷入了困境
into this bloody business,
我就心神不安
it's that, that turns my soul to water.
我是在上一艘船上见到她的
I met her when I was first officer
那时候我是大副
on my last ship.
我要休息
Air.
哦 我得休息一下 克洛克先生
Oh I need air, Mr. Croker.
我从来没有这么跳过舞
I've never danced so much in my life.
你天生就是个舞者 弗莱泽小姐
You dance if you were born to Miss Fraser.
我保证 这既不是天生的也不是后天培养
Neither born nor bred, I assure Mr. Croker.
我想是因为我有个更会跳舞的舞伴
Led to it, I think, by a better dancer than I am.
她对待我就和
She treated me as fairly
一般的女人对男人那样
as ever a woman treated a man.
我们从来没有订过婚
We were never engaged.
我并没有怨言
I have no complaints.
我只是一厢情愿地爱着她
But it was all love on my side
她只是把我当朋友看待
and all-good comradeship and friendship on hers.
当我们分开的时候
When we parted
她仍无所牵挂
she was a free woman
我却再也不是个了无牵挂的人
but I could never again be a free man.
当我再次航海归来的时候
Next time I came back from the sea
我听说她结婚了
I read of her marriage.
这似乎是她本应就该得到的
It seemed to be the sort of thing she was made for.
我并不悲伤
I didn't grieve.
相反我觉得很高兴
I felt it to be right.
我没想到还会再遇到她
So I never thought to see her again.
上次航行以后我被提升
At last voyage I was promoted,
而新船还没下海
and the new boat was not yet launched,
所以我要和我的水手们
so I had to wait for a couple of months
在肯特等两个月
with my people in Kent.
我知道她在那 可是我没有去见她
I knew now where she was but stayed away.
有一天我遇到了梯芮萨・瑞特
Then I met Theresa Wright one day
她告诉了我关于她的一切
and she told me all about her,
包括那段婚姻
about the marriage,
她残酷的醉鬼丈夫
about the man's drunken cruelty,
以及所有的事
about everything.
你们知道那位崇高的男爵
Do you know this noble baron
烧掉了她的宠物
had burnt her pet dog
还威胁她吗
and threatened as much to her?
先生们 我告诉你们
I tell you gentlemen,
这简直要让我气疯了
it nearly drove me mad.
我确实见到了玛丽
I did meet Mary
之后我又见了她一次
and I met her again.
最后
At last,
她不想再见我了
she would meet me no more.
接着我接到通知
I was then given notice
要在一周内出海
that I would leave of my voyage within the week.
你疯了
You're mad.
你怎么能来这呢
How could you come here?
我马上就要离开了 玛丽
I'm to go away Mary.
他们给了我艘船
I've been given a ship.
我马上就走了 我想向你道别
To go and not say farewell.
我也许再也没法见到你了
I thought I might never see you again.
你要走了?
You're going away?
我一点也不为此开心
I do not relish it.
你会是个好船长的
You'll make a fine captain.
你千万不要错过
You must not let anything
这个大好机会
spoil such an opportunity.
我对你是有感情的
I feel for you.
可你无能为力
You can do nothing.
这是最让我伤心的事情
However, it is which hurts most stunning.
我觉得我这几周
I believe I should have gone mad
都快要疯了
these past few weeks.
玛丽?
Lf... Mary?
如果我没有这么想你
If it had not been for the thought of you,
我的朋友
my friend.
好吧
Alright.
是朋友就好 玛丽
Friend will do, Mary.
这就是我对你的爱
It is the measure of my love for you
它如此强烈 将永存于我的心中
it's so strong it will live on crumbs.
朋友就好
Friend will do.
杰克 你别这么说
Jack don't even say it.
这并不会让我们更开心
It won't make us any happier.
你知道我的感觉
You know what I feel.
我知道吗
Do I?
你知道的
You know you do.
那么我要比我来的时候更喜悦了
Then I shall go a happier man than when I came.
上帝保佑你 亲爱的玛丽・弗莱泽
God Bless you sweet Mary Fraser.
这对我来说已经足够
That's enough for me.
我必须走了 杰克
You must not stay Jack.
看在我的份上 把这个带走吧
Take this for my sake.
我终于抓住你们了 夫人
At last I have you madam.
这就是你见不得人的事
At your taint.
这就是你该死的端庄的真面目吗
Here's a key to your damn modesty.
你还有什么想说的吗 夫人
You have a confession madam?
一个该死的妓女
A damn whore,
一个贫穷的贱人
A gutter queen,
一个肮脏的荡妇
A filthy jade.
是的 先生
Yes sir.
来吧
Come sir.
站在这
Stand you there, sir,
不要管那个该死的妓女了
over the body of your bloody harlot.
她没事
She's all right.
杰克?
Jack?
哦 杰克
Oh Jack.
谢谢你 船长
Thank you. My captain.
把这个喝了
Now drink this.
哦 发生了什么
Oh... oh what happened?
我杀了他
I killed him.
什么?
Are you certain?
我杀了他
I know.
我早就想到会有今天了
I felt it.
哦 老天
Oh dear God.
我们该怎么办
What are we going to do?
听老梯芮萨的话
Listen to your old Theresa.
你被打了一拳
You're marked with a blow
这差点要了你的命
that could have killed you,
这也许是你解脱的机会
that shall be your salvation.
梯芮萨异常的冷静
Theresa was as cool as ice.
这是她和我的密谋
It was her plot as much as mine.
我们必须让一切看起来
We must make it appear
好像是强盗做的
the burglars had done the thing.
梯芮萨一再给她的女主人
Theresa kept on repeating
重复我们编造的故事
our story to her mistress,
而我爬上去
while I swarmed up
切断铃绳
and cut the rope of the bell.
然后我把玛丽绑在椅子上
I then lashed for her in her chair,
把绳子的末端弄成磨损的样子
frayed out the end of the rope
来让一切看起来自然些
to make it look natural.
银器的事你们都知道了
The silver well you know about that.
是的 那三个装着酒的杯子
I do, and the third glass of port
就是为了嫁祸给阮达尔吧?
to tie in with the Randalls?
是的
Yes.
然后我们把烛台
And we dropped the candlestick
扔在玛丽摔倒的地方
by where Mary fell
这样蜡就会溅到她身上
for the wax would splash on her.
我以为警察永远
I never thought the police
不会识破我们的计谋
could have seen through our dodge.
当我知道那个野蛮人已经死了
When I knew that savage fiend was dead
她也可以自由的时候
and she was free of him
我就把那晚看作是我生命中最美的一晚
I reckon I done the best nights work of my life.
即使我被绞死我也会做这么做的
I still do even if I swing for it.
这就是真相
That is the truth.
全部的事实 先生
The whole truth, sir.
老天
Dear God.
没错
Yes.
是的 你告诉了我们一切
Yes you have told me the truth.
如果那个女仆
And if the lady's maid
能够不要那么节约
had been less abstemious
处理了那几个杯子
and accepted your glass of port,
也许你就可以骗过我了
your ingenuity might have fooled me
就像你已经骗过了警察那样
as you have certainly fooled the police.
谁把你的方向引向我的
Who put you onto me?
你如何找到我的
How on earth did you find me?
只有杂技演员或水手
No one could have gone after that bell rope
才能够到铃绳
but an acrobat or sailor.
只有水手
No one but a sailor
会打那把椅子上的
could have made the knots
那种方式的绳结
with which the cord was fastened to the chair.
那位夫人在那种情况下
It was evident that the lady was shielding someone
依旧在庇护别人
to do so under such circumstances
说明她爱那个人
meant that she must love the person.
把她和她来这国家时
Was that too wild a leap of the imagination
所乘坐的船上的船员联系起来
to connect her with an officer of a ship,
也并不是太难 不是么
which brought her to this country?
克洛克
Croker.
你在等一个人
You're expecting a visitor.
我有吗?
I am?
这位先生知道所有的事
My dearest the gentleman that knows everything.
所以不必对他有所隐瞒
There's no hiding from it.
我知道了
I Know.
他的电报让我来这的
His telegram brought me here.
你有什么打算 福尔摩斯先生
What do you intend, Mr. Holmes?
克洛克船长
Well Captain Croker
这是个非常严重的事件
this is a very serious matter.
虽然我非常确定基于你今晚
Yet I feel sure that on the basis of the story,
告诉我的故事
which you have told us here tonight,
大英帝国的法庭会理解
a British court of law will understand
你的行为是出于自卫
that you acted in defense of your own life.
但是 这一切
That, however,
必须要由陪审团决定
is for the jury to decide.
不过
Meanwhile,
我非常同情你
I have so much sympathy for you
因此你可以选择在
that if you choose to disappear
24小时内消失
within the next 24-hours
我保证没有人会阻拦你
I promise no one will hinder you.
这样就可以没事了?
Then it will all come out?
肯定不会有什么事了
Certainly it will come out.
这算是什么馊主意啊
What sort of proposal is that?
玛丽必须要承担所有的后果
Mary would be left to face the music.
甚至作为共犯被拘禁
Held as an accomplice maybe.
不 先生 我不会这么做的
No sir, it will not do.
杰克 你必须走
Jack you must go.
我不会的
I shall not.
船长 平静下来
Calm yourself Captain.
我只是在试探你
I was only testing you.
华生 这家伙次次都是说的真话
Watson, this fellow rings true every time.
我需要承担
It is a great responsibility
极大的责任
that I take upon myself
但是我们会
but we will do it
按照法律程序来解决的
in due form of law.
克洛克 你是犯人
Croker, you are the prisoner.
华生
Watson?
你是一位英国陪审员
You are a British jury,
我从未见过一个
and I never met any man
比你更合适担任陪审员的人了
more eminently fitted to represent one.
现在 先生
Now gentle man
你已经听取了证词
you have heard the evidence
你认为这个犯人有罪还是无罪
do you find the prisoner guilty or not guilty.
无罪
Not guilty.
人民的呼声便是上帝的呼声
Vox populi, vox Dei.
克洛克船长 你无罪释放了
You are acquitted,Captain Croker.
不
No.
不 先生你不能这么做
No sir it will not do.
船长?
Captain?
如果警察抓了其他可怜的无辜者怎么办
What if the police arrest some other poor devil,
怎么办
what then?
我就会运用我全部的能力
Then I will use all my powers
来劝说他们相信自己抓错了人
to persuade them of their mistake.
如果他们偶然发现了你
If they light on you
那就是另外一回事了
then that is another matter.
不过 我认为这不太可能
However, I think that is unlikely.
一年后你再回到这位夫人身边吧
Come back to this lady in a year's time,
但愿你和她的未来都能证明
and may her future and yours justify
我们今晚作出的
us in the judgment that we
判决是正确的
have pronounced this night.
哦 谢谢你
Oh thank you.
夫人 我很好奇
Madam, I'm intrigued,
对于一个可悲的酗酒鬼
you gave such a compelling account
你是如何做出如此真实的描述的?
of the man's sad addiction to drink
因为据我们所知
and yet it is not as we now know
你的丈夫并非如此
portrayed as your husband
可你的描述又如此的令人信服
but it was such a clear description I wondered.
那是我的父亲
My father.
我可怜的父亲 医生
My poor father, Doctor.
他正因为这个赶来英国
He's on his way England because of it.
正是他的自律
His self-management was the reason
才让我并不害怕我丈夫的恶习
I didn't fear the vice of my husband
因为我们结婚前我就知道这个了
because I knew of it before we were married.
我真是个傻瓜
How foolish I was.
谢谢你 夫人
Thank you madam.
我非常确定你故事的真实性
I felt sure that your story was true to reality.
祝你好运
Good luck to you.
你似乎并不太赞成
It's almost as though you disapproved
我们今天促成的好事
of the happiness we have fostered this day.
不 我赞成你的决定 我当然是赞成的
Oh no, I approve of that, of course I do.
但是你让我
But I'm uneasy
又做律师又做法官的
that you took upon yourself the duties
这对我来说可不容易
of advocate and judge.
华生 你被条条框框束缚住了
You are too bound by forms, Watson.
福尔摩斯 社会就是条条框框组成的
Forms are society, Holmes.
人不能没有规矩 福尔摩斯
Manners make a man, Holmes.
幸好你是独一无二的
It's just as well you are unique.
破烂熊字幕组
-==http://www.ragbear.com==-
欢迎加入